OMAR ABDULRAHMAN



716-473-4869



omarabdulrahman41@gmail.com



Clarence, NY 14031

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Professional hard working developer with over 7 years of experience and a growing passion in creating the best solutions for the most challenging problems. Currently in love with the React stack and eager to apply this skillset as much as possible while learning and adapting to more in front end web development. Adaptable, communicative and can effectively work independently.

EXPERIENCE

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER, Clarence, NY

React Front End Web Development, June 2019-March 2024

- Upgraded a Progressive Web App for a client which keeps track of top 5 favorite social media profiles from several sites, from ReactRouter v5 to v6. Increased hot reload performance from create-react-app to Vite(instead of create-react-app), and Redux to Redux Toolkit/Redux Toolkit Query
- Replaced inefficient Mongoose queries which increased readability. Backend api service with Node/Express/MongoDB&Mongoose
- JWT token authentication for user login
- Improved mobile views with CSS container queries for seamless responsiveness.
- Better centralized api error handling with Redux Toolkit Query middlware, and visual updates from Toastify.
- Saved server resources through data caching/memoizing & automatic refresh of data per invalidating request with Redux Toolkit Query
- Moved to Vitest from enzyme.

REACT SOFTWARE ENGINEER AT VIBRENT HEALTH, Clarence, NY

React Front End Web Development

- Implemented multi step/page form routing, custom form validation & data caching across all nine modules with redux & redux form
- Ensured minimum 90% unit test coverage with Jest/Enzyme/React Testing Library for each module.
- Added several cross-team reusable UI components including pinned data tables, server pagination, async dynamic select options, and enhanced styling switching bootstrap with material-ui which greatly improved readability, reduced boiler plate, improved overall page layout and component performance.
- Agile trained and provided helpful long term suggestions to product managers to improve story/ticket pointing.
- Took initiative to standardize product design with designers with Zeplin and implemented user testing feedback which increased survey satisfaction feedback.
- Drafted web accessibility guidelines for multi team use to prepare for future requirements.

C# & REACT SOFTWARE ENGINEER, US

inlighten, February 2017-November 2017

Redesigned and programmed their old main media player, transferred relevant modules from VB6 to C#.

- Researched tools to add new effects to current displays with DirectX, WinTV. Panning audio, visual display effects, easier user controls.
- Debugged playback issues on Windows, including display resolutions and audio problems.

JAVASCRIPT/CSS & DYNAMICS NAV DEVELOPER, Buffalo, NY

Gemko, December 2015-October 2016

- Programmed and modified Dynamics NAV business logic using C/AL language to suit clients' needs.
- Engaged in researching new tools utilizing C# to enhance existing features.
- Assisted clients on-site and remotely with any IT problems as well as installation of the software and guidance through use of the software.
- Redesigned parts of their main website with the latest Bootstrap features to be more responsive and mobile friendly

EDUCATION

COMPLETED COURSEWORK TOWARDS BACHELOR OF SCIENCE (B.S.) IN COMPUTER INFORMATION SYSTEMS

State university of New York